本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： leslie仙仙 猫 魔法莉露姆 海之南
校对/后期： 海之南
没有什么能比得上戈德堡家的感恩节
There was nothing quite like Thanksgiving in the Goldberg house.
我妈妈全心全意地准备
My mom gave it her heart and soul,
她所想要的回报只是
and all she wanted in return
她的家人都坐在桌子旁
was her family to sit around the table
感谢...她
and give thanks... to her.
好了 火鸡烤好了 洋芋也加了糖稀
Okay, turkey's been basted, and the yams are marshmallowed.
大功告成
My job is done.
也许现在该你们行动起来了
Maybe it's time for you to do your jobs
在接下来几个小时里好好想想
and spend the next few hours thinking about
你最感谢的人或者事是什么
the thing or person that you're most thankful for.
邦・乔维的美臀
Bon Jovi's ass.
乐队歌手
达里尔・道金斯
Darryl Dawkins.
NBA传奇中锋
哈里森・福特
Harrison Ford.
美国著名影星 作品《夺宝奇兵》《星球大战》等
他是印第安纳・琼斯 韩・索罗
He's Indiana Jones, Han Solo,
分别为福特在夺宝奇兵和星球大战中的角色
鲜为人知的是 他是个训练有素的木匠
and--little-known fact-- he's a trained carpenter.
他能给我们做一个凉亭
He can make us a gazebo.
出去了 去换好衣服
Everyone out. Go get dressed
想想你们的答案
and think about your answers
而我就在这儿埋头苦干
while I'm here slaving away.
在《银翼杀手》里他没受到赏识
And he was underappreciated in "Blade Runner."
哈里森・福特逊毙了
Harrison Ford sucks.
你是说没受到赏识吗
"Underappreciated," you say?
那确实逊毙了
That does suck.
我们谁都不该这么说
Which none of us should be saying.
这是个很不好的词
That's a terrible word.
但是我们没有上楼去换衣服...
But instead of going upstairs to change...
而是去楼下...
We went downstairs...
玩有史以来最棒的游戏
To play the greatest sport of all time.
像所有无聊的同胞一样
Like all bored siblings, my brother and I
哥哥和我发明了无数不同的游戏...
invented a ton of different games...
战役球
Battle-ball!
但这个是我们的最爱 叫做...
But this was our favorite. It was called...
球球 进了
Ball-ball! Yes!
那个是突围 所以是六分
That was on a breakaway, so it's 6 points
额外再加一轮
plus a bonus round!
与所有我和哥哥玩的游戏一样
Like every game I played with my big brother,
我一次也没赢过
I had never once won.
太悲哀了 甚至球球的纪念品
It was so bad, the ball-ball trophy
都是以他命名的
was even named after him.
这个让人觊觎的巴里杯
And the coveted Barry cup
又一次...
once again goes to...
投向巴里...
Barry...
诺曼...
Norman...
- 戈德堡的怀抱 - 嘿 嘿 别玩了
- Goldberg! - Hey, hey! Knock it off.
别玩这个球球了
Enough with the ball-ball.
你们妈妈让你们去换衣服
Your mother told you to get dressed.
她也让你换
She told you, too.
我还差一步就好了 你还差四步
I'm one move away. You're four!
马上行动
Now move it!
我不会让你们毁了你们妈妈的感恩节的
I'm not gonna have you ruin your mother's thanksgiving.
但并不总是我们毁了老妈的感恩节
But it wasn't us that always ruined thanksgiving.
不 那个名号属于我的叔叔马文
No, that title went to my uncle Marvin.
可是 真的 为什么我们每年都得邀请他
But, seriously, why do we have to invite him every year?
因为马文是你的兄弟 是你唯一的家人
'Cause Marvin's your brother and the only family you've got?
不 我有你 我有她叫什么来着
No. I've got you, I got what's-her-name,
我有地下室里那两个笨蛋
I got the two morons in the basement.
我很好
I'm good.
看 每年你们都要打架
Look, every year you two fight,
甚至在我们坐下之前马文就离席而去
and Marvin ends up storming out before we even sit down.
就这一次 你就不能把所有消极的感觉
For once, can't you just take all the negative feelings
- 变成积极的吗 - 怎么变
- and spin them into a positive? - How?!
他甚至从没有过工作
He's never even had a job.
换成正面影响 他是个无拘无束的人
Positive spin-- he's a free spirit.
你不能给那个标价
You can't put a price on that.
从九百元开始怎么样
How's 900 bucks for starters?
那是我给他参加酒吧侍者学校付的学费
That's how much I paid for his bartending school,
然后他不及格被退学了 谁会干这种事
and he flunked out. Who does that?
我来告诉你谁会
I'll tell you who.
电影"花心情圣"中的汤姆克鲁斯
Tom Cruise in the movie "Cocktail,"
你知道最后他怎么样了么
and you know how that ended for him.
这个 其实 我没看过这部电影
Well, actually, I never saw that movie,
不过我猜他凭借他美妙的酒
but I assume he won over the whole city
赢得了全市的美誉
with his fancy drinks.
好
Fine!
当他到了这儿 我会试着对他好一点的
When he gets here, I will try and be nice to him.
你知道吗 亲爱的 带着新的积极的态度
You know what, hon? With a new positive attitude,
我想马文会让你大吃一惊的
I think Marvin's really gonna surprise you.
德劳瑞恩
Delorean!
的确大吃一惊
Surprise.
最近咋样 默
What's up, Mur?
戈德堡一家 第一季09集
那是在一九八几年的感恩节
It was thanksgiving day, 1980-something,
我终于找到了
and I had finally discovered
可以和我叔叔聊天的话题
I had something to talk about with my uncle.
它有通量电容器吗
Does it have a flux capacitor?
它工作时是1.21千兆瓦吗
Does it run on 1.21 gigawatts?
你有被恐怖分子追捕过吗
Have you been chased by terrorists?
没 不过我有被女士们追捕过...
No, but I have been chased by the ladies...
因为那是个美臀磁铁
'Cause it's a ass magnet!
好了 问差不多了
Okay, enough questions.
恩 马文 要喝点什么吗
Um, Marv, can I get you something to drink?
额 不 你要喝点什么吗
Uh, no. Can I get you something to drink?
不是每天你的屋子里
It's not every day you got a semiprofessional bartender
都会有一个半职业的酒保 对吧
in your house, am I right?
嘿 鸡尾酒 嘿 呦 呦
Hey! Cocktail! Hey! Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
哈 马文 看起来不错
Ho! Marv-o! Lookin' good!
马上为您效劳 要哪种酒 艾尔
Right back at you. What's your poison, Al?
我要一杯金汤力
I'll take a gin and tonic.
太烈了 过
Too hard. Pass.
要葡萄酒或者蓝色夏威夷
Say wine or blue hawaiian.
我哪个都不想要
I really don't want either one of those.
好了  那就葡萄酒  下一个到谁
All right, wine it is. Who's next?
默哥 你要什么
Mur, what can I do you for?
我想知道车道上那东西 你是怎么买来的
I'd like to know how you paid for that thing in the driveway.
- 默里 - 怎么啦 我很积极啊
- Murray. - What?! I'm being positive.
我只是想了解下我弟弟的情况
I just want to know about my brother.
没关系
Uh, uh, no, no, no.
这问题问得很好
No, no, it's a perfectly fair question,
尤其是考虑到我们的过去
given our history.
说出来你们肯定不信
You guys aren't gonna believe me,
但是我真的找到了工作
but I actually got a job.
是吗 就像你在瑞典一样卖分时计算器吗
Yeah, like those time-shares in Sweden that you were selling.
或者就像我投资的驼羊牧场 我干的怎么样
Or like that alpaca farm I invested in. How did I do?
不怎样 它们生病了 弄伤了一些孩子
Not good. They got sick, they hurt some kids.
挺悲伤的事
Sad stuff.
不管怎样 我找到了一份普通的工作
Anyways, I got a regular old job.
穿套装 朝九晚五
I wear a suit. I work 9:00 to 5:00,
就像我大哥一样
just like my big bro here.
说到这儿...
Speaking of which...
我想还钱给你 一点点
I want to pay you back. A little bit.
我以前欠你的一些
For some of the money that I owe you.
这差不多有两千美金
There's like $2,000 in here.
是的 这只是九牛一毛 但起码是个开始
Yeah, it's a drop in the bucket, uh, but it's a start.
过来 过来
Come here. Come here.
- 这是第一次... - 过来
- For the first time... - Come here.
我爸爸对马文
My dad felt something for Marvin
感到从未有过的骄傲
he'd never felt before... pride.
太好啦
It's happening!
我们大家都坐在这边 表达一下感谢吧
Oh. Hey, let's all sit at the table and give thanks.
趁现在有气氛 快点
Right now, before it gets too late.
为了带这个人兜风 我已经等了
I have been waiting all month to give this guy
一个月啦
a ride in my car.
- 默里 你觉得呢 - 去兜风
- Mur, what do you say? - Let's ride.
默里老兄
Mur-man!
# 乘车 #
Motorin'
# 为了寻找另一半 #
what's your price for flight
# 你飞行的代价是什么 #
in finding Mr. Right
# 你今晚就会没事的 #
you'll be all right tonight
我听不懂这歌
I do not understand that song.
瞧瞧我们
Look at us.
像以前一样绕着詹金顿巡游
Cruisin' around Jenkintown like back in the day.
瞧瞧我们
Look at us, huh?
这是对深海乳液的致谢
And it's all thanks to lotions of the oceans.
- 乳液啥 - 我的新工作
- Lotions of the what? - It's my new job.
我是销售乳液的
I'm a lotioneer.
我卖面霜
I sell these facial creams
身体乳 它们中加入了
and body butters, and they're infused
海盐
with this real sea salt.
美好的东西 默... 你取少量这种东西
Beautiful thing, Mur... you take a dab of this stuff,
敷在你的脸上
you put it on your face,
你的皮肤就变得又滑又嫩
and your skin becomes so smooth and soft.
不管是什么吧 对你好就行
Well, whatever it is, good for you.
对你也有好处
Well, could be good for you.
只是一点现金投资
Just a little cash investment,
你就在低价的时候开始了这赚钱的生意
you get in on the ground floor of this killer business.
- 什么 - 只是这一次
- What? - Just this time
我听起来好像会有什么变化
you made it sound like it was gonna be different.
是有变化
It is different.
马文 我很想支持你
Marvin, I so want to support you,
但是你让我很难做
but you make it so hard.
你不相信我 没事 你摸摸我的脸
You don't believe me. Fine. Touch my face.
什么
What?
先别这么快做决定
Stop being so judgy for five seconds,
你摸摸我的脸 你就知道
and touch my face, and then you will understand
我的皮肤有多么好
how smooth and delightful my skin is.
- 摸一下 - 我不想摸你的脸
- Touch it. - I don't want to touch your face.
- 摸一下 - 我都不摸我老婆的脸
- Touch my face! - I don't even touch my wife's face.
就摸一下
Touch my face!
这摸起来一点都不像一个男人的皮肤
It's like I'm all man, except for this one tiny spot.
我才不摸
I'm not touching your face.
就像摸到婴儿的耳垂一样
It's like a little baby's earlobe!
你疯啦
You're out of your mind.
- 算啦 停车 - 什么
- That's it! Pull over! - What?
从我的驾驶座上下来
Remove yourself from the cockpit of my car!
我的爸爸不是唯一一个跟他弟弟享受
My dad wasn't the only one spending quality time
美好时光的人
with his brother.
决胜球
Battle-ball!
进啦 进啦
Yes! Yes!
刚刚是左手得分 我赢了两分
That's a left-handed goal! 2 points for me,
巴里又赢啦
and Barry wins again!
等等 等等 等等 你没有说"球球"
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. You didn't call "ball-ball."
- 我说啦 - 不 你没有说 我听着呢
- Yes, I did. - No, you didn't. I was sitting right here.
那就要减两分 再罚一球
That's minus 2 points, plus a penalty shot.
- 站好 - 无所谓 没什么大不了
- Line up. - Whatever. Like it matters.
我当时没有想到
I didn't realize it at that moment,
但是当巴里用抱枕护住了他的腹部
but as Barry covered his groin with a throw pillow,
我们的整个局势就戏剧性的逆转了
our entire power dynamic was about to shift.
爆头 五分
Head-shot! 5 points!
不对 没有打中我的头
Nuh-unh! Didn't hit my head.
打中了 我看到了
Uh... Yes, it did. I was just watching.
我赢了 我赢了
I just won. I just won!
我刚刚赢了"球球"
I just won at ball-ball!
太假了 你根本不可能赢
Not true! There's no way you just won!
我很确定他赢了
I'm pretty sure he just won.
这个笨笨的四眼仔根本
There isn't a world where this little,
不可能打败我
unathletic, lazy-eyed nerd would beat me.
好吧 这个笨笨的四眼仔
Well, this unathletic, lazy-eyed nerd
刚刚赢了"球球"的冠军
is now ball-ball champion!
我创造了历史
History had been made,
而且跟任何一个冠军一样...
and I did what any champion would...
得意洋洋
Gloat.
我就知道 你不怀好意
I knew it! I knew you had an angle!
- 什么 - 你引诱我进入你的破车
- What? - You trapped me in your stainless steel box
就为了找我要钱
just to ask me for money!
不是找你要钱 我只是给你提供一个
It's not asking for money! I'm only telling you about
此生仅有的投资机会
the investment opportunity of a lifetime,
只花两千块
and it's gonna cost you $2,000.
你刚还了我两千块
You just paid me back $2,000!
那你就有钱投资了
So you have it!
你一定要当个大笨蛋吗
You have to be the biggest moron of all time.
笨蛋能开那么酷的车吗
Would a moron drive an awesome car like that?!
- 你买保险了吗 - 怎么啦 不
- Do you have insurance? - Why?! No!
天哪
Oh, my god!
不
No!
你没拉上手刹啊
You didn't put the parking brake on!
傻帽 不 求你了
Moron! No! Please!
傻帽 天哪
Moron! Oh, gosh!
好吧 只有一个刮痕
Okay. Uhh! It's just a dent!
只有一个刮痕
It's just a dent.
算你好运 这货是美国生产的
You're lucky this thing was built in America.
你把车门弄歪了
You bent the frame!
是的 车门变形了
Yep. He bent the frame.
但我觉得车子比以前更酷炫
I thought the car looked even more awesome like this.
嘿 伙计
Hey, pal.
但我叔叔可不这么觉得
But my uncle did not agree.
- 他把车门撞歪了 - 啥...真的吗
- He bent the frame! - What--really?
他把车门撞歪了
He bent the frame!
现在我爸跟马文叔叔总算能相处
Now that my dad and uncle Marv were getting along,
我妈终于要收获对她的感谢了
my mom was finally gonna get her thanks.
好的 他们回来了
Okay, they're back!
但或许只是她一厢情愿
Or so she thought.
各位...
Everyone...
让我们坐在桌旁 致感恩词吧
Let's all sit at the table and say our thanks...
想对谁说都可以
to whoever that may be.
贝弗 很抱歉
Bevy, I am so sorry.
我知道你希望今年不同于往年
I know you wanted this year to be different,
但事实是
but it turns out
什么都没变
some things never change!
我告诉你什么变了
I'll tell you what's changed.
我再也不会回到这儿了
I'm never coming back here again.
你每年都这么说 但你还不是每年都来
You say that every year, but you keep showing up!
是 没错 但我这次是认真的
Yeah, well, this time I mean it!
我要打电话给德劳瑞恩的
I'm gonna call Delorean's
二十四小时维修热线
24-hour concierge maintenance line,
让他们过来修我的车
come fix my car...
然后我就走
And then I am so out of here!
不 谁都不准走
No! No one's going anywhere!
火鸡都烤好了
The turkey's out of the oven.
以前都没等到这个时候
We've never made it this far!
您拨打的电话无法接通
The number you have called has been disconnected.
出什么幺蛾子
What the hell?
他们不是倒闭了吗
Aren't they out of business?
你说啥
What are you talking about?
新闻上到处都是啊
It was all over the news.
那个经理 约翰・德劳瑞恩 他被捕了
The owner--John Delorean-- he was arrested
因为他想卖可卡因
for trying to sell two F.B.I. Agents
给两个联邦调查局的特工
cocaine powder.
你说啥
What are you saying to me?
说真的 这屋子里的负能量真是满的要爆炸了
Seriously, the negativity in this house is unbelievable!
哟 干嘛呢
Yo! Ad-rock! What's up?
听着 我想了很久
Listen, I've given it a lot of thought,
我决定发表官方声明 我承认
and I've decided to officially acknowledge
- 巴里杯是你赢的 - 应该叫亚当杯了
- that you won the Barry cup. - The Adam cup.
可以啊 重点是 我是个真男人
Sure. Point is, is I'm being a man
大度地承认你赢了
and agreeing that you won.
现在轮到你做真男人 跟我玩球
Now you be a man and play me in ball-ball
那样我才能赢回奖杯
so I can win the trophy back.
嗯 但我得告诉你一件事...
Yeah, here's the thing about that...
- 我不玩了 - 啥
- I retired. - What?
关于"球球"游戏
I've basically done all I needed to do
我差不多把能玩的招式都玩够了
on the ball-ball court,
现在我打算玩点别的
and now I'm looking to the future.
你不能赢了奖杯就不玩了 那你就永远是冠军了
You can't retire as champion. It makes you champion forever.
哦 我想是这样
Ooh, I guess it does.
好吧 我会在别的游戏上打败你的
Fine. I'll beat you at something else.
曲棍球 篮球 飞镖
Hockey, basketball, darts,
优诺牌 超级侦探
uno, clue,
超级侦探 源于英国的纸上推理游戏
战舰 掰手腕
battleship, arm wrestling,
战舰 一种纸上海战游戏
掰拇指 甚至真格的摔跤...
thumb wrestling, real wrestling...
随便跟我玩个游戏 我好打败你
Just play me in something so I can beat you in it!
你确定你能赢我
Are you sure you can beat me?
也许战斗力转移到我这里
Or has the power dynamic shifted,
你再也赢不了任何游戏了呢
and you'll never win anything ever again?
你是认真的吗
Are you serious right now?
从现在开始 你不再是大哥了
From now on, you're not the big brother anymore.
我才是
I am.
我永远都是大哥
I will always be the big brother.
我今年长了两英寸的个子
I've grown 2 inches this year.
你呢
How much have you grown?
我不会回答这种蠢问题
I don't have to answer that.
管好自己的事吧 因为从现在起
Get your affairs in order, 'cause from now on,
我是男子汉了
I'm the man.
现在...离我远一点
Now... Leave me to my robot.
当巴里的怒火逐渐升温时
While Barry's anger was heating up,
我妈精心准备的感恩节大餐要冷掉了
my mom's perfect thanksgiving was cooling down.
天哪...
Dude...
我快撑死了
I'm so stuffed!
等等 你从哪儿回来
Wait a minute. Where are you coming from?
我刚刚去了蕾妮家
I just ran over to Lainey's house.
她妈妈做的饭简直好吃到升天
Her mom made the most amazing feast.
我得躺下来
I need to lie down.
你最好留点肚子
Well, you better make room in your body,
因为这是感恩节
because this thanksgiving is happening.
我得向你坦白 贝弗
I gotta be honest with you, Bev.
我今天屡受打击
I'm taking a lot of body blows today.
真他妈太受打击了
Whole lot of body blows.
很显然 不仅是德劳瑞恩门店
Apparently, in addition to Delorean
没了全天修车服务
discontinuing their 24-hour concierge service,
我现在哪儿都买不到车子配件
now it's impossible for me to buy spare parts,
因为那家汽车公司倒闭了
because the company no longer exists!
真希望我买车之前有人能告诉我这件事
Really wish someone would have told me that before I bought the car.
我现在得叫出租车了
Point is, I'm calling a cab.
不 别叫出租车
No! No cabs!
我刚刚切好了火鸡 马文
I just cut the turkey, Marvin.
别这样
Come on.
我妈知道她伟大的感恩节感恩计划
My mom knew her big thanksgiving thank-you...
即将化为泡影
was going down the drain,
所以她准备动用每一份力量
so she decided to use every ounce of manipulation
甚至情感勒索
and emotional blackmail in her arsenal
来确保这事不会发生
to make sure that didn't happen.
她可以唱红脸...
She was good cop...
我知道你有个很邋遢的爹
I know you had a lousy father
你跟马文度过的童年很艰难
and your childhood with Marvin was very complicated.
我都了解 我永远站在你这边
I get it. I am on your side.
她也可以唱白脸...
She was bad cop...
我很生气 马文
I'm getting angry, Marvin.
你不会想看到我生气的
You won't like me when I'm angry.
她还可以装内疚...
She was guilt cop...
我差一点点就想放弃做一个妻子
I am this close to giving up as a wife,
一个母亲 甚至一个人类了
as a mother, and as a human being.
最后 她甚至于干脆就撒谎了
And finally, she was the crooked cop that just plain lied.
你知道默里有多高傲
You know how prideful Murray is.
他刚明白告诉我
He literally just told me
他想投资你的公司
he wants to invest in your company,
只是他不知道该怎么说出口
but he doesn't know how to say it.
马文想向前看
Marvin wants to just move on
忘掉他跟你提过的这笔生意
and forget he ever mentioned the business to you.
没理由再提起了
There's no reason to ever bring it up again.
这是默里给你的支票 他希望你能收下
This is the check from Murray. He wants you to have it.
但是
But...
他也希望你不要在提这件事
He also wants you to never mention it.
永远不要提
Ever.
老妈成功施法 有那么几分钟
My mom had worked her magic, and for a few minutes,
还真像置身于一个正常的感恩节
it was actually like being at a normal thanksgiving.
于是我们就去了
So there we were, okay?
康尼・马克体育场
Connie Mack stadium.
山迪・柯法斯刚和我们的
Sandy Koufax just pitched
费城人队来了场无安打赛局
a no-hitter against our Phillies.
他真是太出色了
He was unbelievable.
我们从看台最后的座位冲了下去
We run down from the nose-bleed seats.
真是倾其所有买来的票
That's all we could afford.
你们这些孩子根本不知道自己有多幸福
You kids have no idea how good you got it.
山迪正要走向球员休息区
Sandy is about to go into the dugout.
突然 他回转身来
Suddenly, he turns around,
看着我们 把球扔给了我
he looks at us, throws me the ball.
不对 是他把球扔给我的 因为我接住了
No. He threw me the ball, because I caught it.
他显然是扔给我的
He clearly threw it to me,
所以老爸才强迫你把球给了我
which is why dad made you give me the ball.
是啊 有史以来最棒的投球手
Yeah, the greatest pitcher of all time
站在八英尺开外
from 8 feet away
不知道球是扔给谁的吗
doesn't know what kid he's throwing to?
好了 保持积极心态
Okay. Keeping it positive.
晚餐进行到现在
Uh, now's the time in our dinner
该我们围着餐桌走动
where we're all going to go around the table
说出我们最感谢的是什么事 什么人了
and say what or who we're most thankful for.
明白没 我来带头
All right? I'm gonna start.
我很感激能够与我最迷人可爱的家人在一起
I'm thankful to be surrounded by my beautiful, loving family.
埃里卡
Erica?
我都没法说话 我太撑了
I can't even talk, I'm so full.
好吧 巴里 接下去
Fine. Barry, go.
我要感谢"鳄鱼吃豆子"这款游戏
I'm thankful for the game hungry hungry hippos,
游戏已经在房间摆好了 有人要玩的话随时都可以
which is set up in the den if anyone wants to play.
我也要感谢我的家人
I am also thankful for my family,
我现在要从高到低给咱家列个权势表
which I'll now list from most to least powerful.
老爸 波普斯 老妈 埃里卡
Dad, pops, mom, Erica,
我 马文叔叔
me, uncle Marv,
当然 垫底的是巴里
and of course, dead last, Barry.
你为什么把我放在最后 你不可以这么做
Why are you putting me last? You can't put me last.
- 不可以吗 - 够了 能不能别吵了
- Can't I? - Okay, can we stop arguing
开始感谢真正有意义的人
and start thanking someone meaningful?
为你们含辛茹苦的人
Someone who's done a lot for you?
我要感谢一个一直在我身边陪伴我的小女人
I'm thankful for a little woman who's always been there for me,
不只是今天 多年来一直如此
not just today, but throughout the years.
幸运女神
Lady Luck.
要不是她 达拉斯牛仔队永远不会这么出色
Without her, the cowboys would never have covered the spread.
你们想知道我要感谢谁吗
You guys really want to know what I'm thankful for?
当然 说吧 别憋着
Of course. Come on, don't hold back.
有人特意嘱咐我不要再提此事
Well, I was told specifically not to mention it--
哦 天啊 那就别提了吧
Oh. Oh, boy. Uh, maybe don't.
- 不 我要说 - 算了吧
- Nah, I'm gonna do it. - Or not.
我要感谢我大哥
I am thankful for my big brother,
他是那么相信我
who believed in me enough
投资我的化妆品公司
to invest in my cosmetics venture.
我干啥
I what now?
马文 我们不是说好了不提这个了吗
Marvin, I thought we weren't gonna talk about that.
打住
Stop right there.
我们是要投资什么吗 算我一个
We're investing money in stuff? I'm in.
我爱死你们了
I love you guys.
你们一定会喜欢上深海乳液的
And--and you're gonna love lotions of the oceans.
真正的海盐哦
Real sea salt. Huh?
第二种原料是海藻
Kelp--second ingredient.
我这就去后备车厢拿样品
I'm gonna go get my samples out of the trunk.
你们会喜欢的
You're gonna love it.
所以
So...
还有人想表达一下感恩之情吗
anyone else like to give thanks?
好了 这就是我们的"毁春剂"
Okay, this is our brand-new face revujenator.
我想应该是"回春剂"吧
I think it's rejuvenator.
我想我知道什么是"毁春剂"的
I think I know what revujenator is.
我就是卖这玩意儿的
I'm the guy selling the stuff.
我已经感觉年轻多了 我们要发了
I feel younger already. We're gonna be rich.
奖杯在我这儿 我才是冠军
I have the cup! I'm the champion!
不是这么玩儿的 给我
That's not how it works! Give it back!
你在想什么呢
What were you thinking
- 背着我给马文钱 - 对不起
- giving Marvin money behind my back?! - I'm sorry.
是我搞砸了 但那一瞬间
I screwed up. But for a split second,
我看到你们俩和谐相处 我知道你很开心
I saw you two getting along, and I know you were happy.
好吧 我的确很开心
Fine, I was happy!
但那是因为我以为他长大了
But that's because I thought he'd grown up
不再需要我操心了
and I wouldn't have to take care of him anymore!
好了 听好了
Okay! Here you go.
你可能得从车库里腾出一些空间
You probably want to clear some space out of your garage,
因为你周一会收到
because you're gonna get a delivery
大概二十箱这玩意儿
of about, uh, 20 cases of this stuff on Monday.
我干嘛要二十箱这种废物
Why would I want 20 cases of that crap?
因为你投资了呀 对吧
Because you invested. Right?
我们...我们说好了的
That's--that-- that's the deal.
你...你兜售面霜 然后征召更多的人
You--you peddle the creams, and you recruit more people
来扩大你的销售三角
to expand your sales triangle.
销售三角
Sales triangle?
等等 这不是该死的非法传销吗
Wait. Is this a damn pyramid scheme?
不 不 我们有二十六层销售网好吗
No, no! Th-there's 26 tiers of sales, okay?
最上层的那些家伙挣的钱最多
The guys at the top, they make the most money,
然后像漏斗一样到底层的
and then it funnels down toward the base
三维三角区
of the three-dimensional triangle.
你描述的就是金字塔传销结构啊 笨蛋
You literally just described a pyramid, you idiot!
我算是知道怎么回事了
I see what it is.
我终于靠自己过上好日子了
I'm finally doing well for myself,
当然了 我哥哥 却觉得这是某种骗局
so my brother, of course, thinks it's some kind of a scam!
默里 快别说了 今天是感恩节
Murray, stop it! It's thanksgiving!
那就是传销啊
It's a pyramid!
- 我的脸好疼 - 有灼痛的感觉
- My face hurts. - It's burning real bad.
有灼痛感说明见效了
The burning means that it's working.
效果太强烈了 脸上火烧一般
It's working too much! There's fire on my face!
好了 赶紧擦掉
Okay... Just wipe it off.
- 今天是感恩节呢 - 快回来 那是我的奖杯
- It's thanksgiving. - Come back here! That's my cup!
回来 给我回来
Come back here! Come back here!
我现在疼死了
I'm in a great deal of pain now.
- 你知道吗  - 赶快擦掉
- You know what? - Get it off!
我才不管你们这些人怎么想的
I don't care what you people think.
我绝对支持我的产品
I stand by my product.
这么说 你何不也往脸上涂一些呢
Then, uh, why don't you put it on your face?
你要干嘛
What are you doing?
你之前在车上强烈要求我摸你的脸来着
You wanted me to touch your face so bad in the car.
- 快从我脸上弄掉 - 你误会我了
- Get away from my face. - You're taking it out of context.
- 来嘛  - 情况不一样
- Come on! - That was a different situation!
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
把你的手从他脸上拿开
Get your hand off his face!
今天是...感恩节啊
It's Thanks... Giving!
不 天啊
No! Oh, my god!
- 默里 - 天啊
- Murray! - Oh, my god!
爸爸和叔叔像孩子一样
It was a sad sight watching my dad and uncle
扭作一团真不忍直视
fight like children,
但更可悲的是 马文不得不求人送他回家
but even sadder was that Marvin had to ask for a ride home.
我周一会叫个拖车过去
I'm gonna send a flatbed over on Monday,
如果下雨了
so if it begins to rain,
麻烦用防水布把我的德劳瑞恩盖一下
please cover the Delorean with a tarp or something.
- 你的眼睛怎么样了 - 还有点刺痛
- How's your eye? - Still a little sting-y.
你说的没错
You're right about me.
我是个蠢蛋
I'm a moron.
我的车毁了 我还住在咱父母家
My car's a bust, I still live in our parents' house,
很显然 我竟然蠢得没意识到
and apparently I'm too stupid to realize
那个三角和金字塔形状一样
that a triangle is the same shape as a pyramid.
我也说不清 我只是希望有那么一次
I don't know, I just wish that once
我能做件像样的事 不让你失望 默里
I could do something that didn't disappoint you, Murray.
你干嘛在乎我怎么想
What do you care what I think?
开什么玩笑呢 是你把我拉扯大的
Are you serious? You raised me.
爸爸从来不在我身边 而你一直都在
I mean, dad wasn't there. You were.
- 你是我的榜样 - 千万别
- You're the one I look up to. - Well, don't.
我也只是情非得已
I was just doing what I had to do.
因为我 你放弃了你的童年生活
Yeah, well, you gave up your childhood for me.
别以为我不记得
Don't think I forgot that.
我很高兴那么做了
I was glad to do it.
不 才没有呢
No, you weren't.
你说得对
You're right.
我确实很想去参加我的毕业舞会
I would have liked to have gone to my prom.
是啊 我很抱歉当时喝了清洁剂
Yeah. I'm sorry I ate that detergent.
只是它真的很好闻
It just smelled really good.
重点是 照顾你确实不太容易
Look, the poinis, it wasn't easy looking after you.
但我并不后悔
But I don't regret it.
我叫你蠢蛋的唯一原因
And the only reason I call you a moron...
是因为我希望你能得到最好的
Is because I want the best for you.
- 真的吗 - 当然了
- Really? - Yeah.
等我一下好吗
Hold on a second, all right?
哪儿都别去 我去去就回
Don't go anywhere. I'll... I'll be right back.
事实证明 并不是那辆德劳瑞恩车
Turns out it wasn't the Delorean
迫使我老爸和他弟弟回到过去
that forced my dad and his brother to revisit the past.
而是我爸的破烂旅行车
It was my dad's crappy old station wagon.
我希望你收下这个
I want you to have that.
- 柯法斯的棒球  -是的
- The Koufax ball? - Yeah.
我不能收
I can't!
收下吧  算是对你童年的一丢丢弥补
Take it. Have a little bit of your childhood back.
我们都知道他确实是扔向你的
We both know that he was throwing it to you.
进来吧
Get your butt in here.
抓紧时间 感恩节还没过完呢
Come on. Thanksgiving's not over.
- 我们能谈谈吗 - 不行
- Can we talk? - No.
听着
listen.
看到老爸和马文叔叔的二货表现
After I saw dad and uncle Marv acting like morons,
我觉得 也许我会和你再来一场比赛
I thought, maybe I will give you that rematch.
我还以为你不想呢
Thought you didn't want to
你现在可是大哥呢
'Cause you're the big brother now.
别这样嘛
Oh, come on.
你永远都是我的大哥
You'll always be my big brother.
有史以来第一次 我妈妈得到了她梦寐以求的
For the first time ever, my mom ended up getting
完美感恩节
her perfect thanksgiving.
我们甚至坚持到了甜点环节
We even made it to dessert.
嘿 我可以说几句话吗
Hey. Can I just, uh, say something here?
我觉得我们都该好好感谢你们的妈妈
I think we should give mom a big thanks
花了这么多心思
for working her ass off
让我们大家团聚在一起
and bringing us all together.
来干一杯
Hear, hear.
是啊 贝弗 来喝一杯
Yeah, Bev. Hear, hear.
我所做的一切并非要让你们感恩
That's--that's not why I do it,
但非常感谢你们
but thank you very much.
能得到大家的赏识好开心
It's nice to be appreciated.
对我和巴里来说
As for me and Barry,
一个新的球球时代开始了
a new era of ball-ball had begun,
胜负难测
and it was anybody's game.
他进球了 得分了
He shoots! He scores!
他赢了
He wins!
哈 你没说"球球"
Ah! You didn't say "ball-ball."
真该死
Damn it!
好了 看着我的眼睛
Okay, look me in the eye.
你确定你想当一名真正的
Are you positive that you want to be a serious,
尽职尽责的 专业酒保吗
dedicated, professional bartender?
- 或许吧 - 很好
- Uh, maybe? - Good.
我看到了你的热情
I dig the fire in your belly.
好了 规矩一
Okay, rule number one--
永远记住 没人在意他们点的酒味道如何
Always remember, no one cares what their drink tastes like,
只要服务够养眼 够有派头就成
as long as it's served with flair and panache.
这听上去不太对吧
Uh, that doesn't sound right.
没关系的 听我的指示 好吗
It's okay. Follow my lead, okay?
鸡尾酒 鸡尾酒
Cocktail! Cocktail!
嘿 谁想要...
Hey! Who wants--
这儿他妈是怎么回事啊
What the hell's going on in here?
- 没什么 我们只是...- 你在喝酒吗
- Nothing. We were just-- - Are you drinking?!
没有 我只是...
No! I was just--
赶紧给我滚到楼上去
Get your tuchus upstairs now!
行动
Move it!
戈德堡家的有爱感恩节回忆
你休想弄到吃的
You're not getting a thing to eat!
你该为自己感到羞耻  巴里
You ought to be ashamed of yourself, Barry.
他该为自己感到羞耻
He ought to be ashamed of himself!
- 一会儿就好  - 好了 够了
- Just a few minutes. - Okay, enough of this.
- 我的鞋都湿透了 - 我才不管
- My shoes are soaking wet. - I don't care!
■
更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 shinybbs.com
深影字幕组微博 weibo.com/syfansub